Well, well, Boris the Animal has a visitor.
禽獸鮑裏斯有探監的
I guess one every 40 years is okay.
40年頭一個可以放行
It's a cake.
只是塊蛋糕
I decide what it is.
是什麼我說了才算
Looks like some kind of cake.
看起來像蛋糕
She's clean. Well, not clean, but you know....
沒有異常，不是說沒衣裳哦，你懂的...
Oh, God.
噢，天吶
Boris the Animal...
禽獸鮑裏斯
...you've got a visitor.
有人來看你了
It's just Boris.
是「鮑裏斯」
Your letters have been a soul-nourishing...
你的信對我來說就是
...tonic.
心靈雞湯
And you are much more...
你本人可比
...unconventionally handsome than your photos.
照片上帥多了
This ain't a conjugal visit.
這可不是夫妻探監
So quit your conjugating.
別親了
When's the last time you conjugated anything?
你上次親熱是什麼時候？
I see you've brought me a treat, darling.
親愛的，看到你帶的禮物了
Would you mind cutting this up for us? It's a special day.
你能幫我們切開它嗎？ 今天是個特殊的日子
I'm a romantic like that.
我很浪漫的
Oh, I wouldn't do that.
要是我就不會這麼做
Why's that?
為什麼？
It'll ruin your figure.
會廢了你的手指
You complete me.
你讓我完美無缺
The big one.
大傢伙
Boris! You promised to take me with you!
鮑裏斯！你答應帶我一起走的！
We had a deal!
我們說好的！
Obadiah Price.
奧巴代亞·普賴斯
Yes. I did make you a promise.
是，我是答應你了
Wait. I smell something.
等等，感覺不太對
You can't win, Boris.
- 你無路可逃，鮑裏斯 - 是麼
Let's agree to disagree.
咱們走著瞧
There's too many of us.
我們人數多
Rather hot in here. Mind if I open a window?
這裏太熱了，介意開窗通風嗎？
Sorry, darling. We did love the cake.
對不起，親愛的，蛋糕確實不錯
Let's rewrite history, shall we, K?
讓我們重寫歷史，好嗎，K探員？
Good afternoon.
下午好
Please give your attention to my associate, Agent J.
請大家注意看我的搭檔，J探員
He's going to demonstrate an electro-biomechanical...
他會給大家示範一下
...neural-transmitting, zero-synapse repositioner.
電子生物神經傳送零復位裝置
We call it the neuralyzer.
我們叫它記憶消除器
-Keep it simple, slick. -Thanks a lot.
- 簡單點，滑頭 - 多謝
Thank you, Agent K.
感謝J探員
Ladies and gentlemen, if you will look right here.
女士們，先生們，如果你們看這裏
You know how you're on a plane and you're asked to turn your phone off?
就會知道你們是如何登上飛機的 並且空姐讓你們關手機
You're like, "l ain't turning it off. Has nothing to do with a plane."
你們卻想「為什麼要關，也沒破壞飛機」
Well, this is what we get. That's what happens.
看見沒，結果就是這樣
It gets up there, bounces around on the satellites and:
飛機竄到衛星那兒把它轟了下來！
Just turn your damn phone off.
關掉手機不就沒這事了
Now you're gonna drive off a cliff tonight because your GPS don't work.
今晚你們開車要掉下懸崖了 因為沒GPS信號
Check the composition of the fuel units and surface deposits.
查查燃料和表層堆積物的成分
I wanna know who was driving.
我想知道誰在駕駛
Yes, sir.
是的，長官
-What are you gonna say tonight? -Don't worry.
今晚想說什麼？ 別擔心
No, I'm very worried. This is important.
能不擔心嗎，這很重要
-I'm hungry. You hungry? -K.
- 我餓了，你呢？
Seriously, I'm not even sure that's meat.
說真的，我不認為那是肉
I think I just saw a tooth in that thing. Or a claw. Or a hoof.
我想我看到了裏面有 牙齒、爪子、蹄子什麼的
Thanks, Manny.
謝謝，曼尼
That does not belong in a pita, it belongs in a casket.
這根本不是皮塔餅（希臘小吃類似肉夾饃） 應該是棺材餅
What would go good with this would be silence.
能不能少說兩句
See, here's the problem.
看吶，這就是問題所在
You can't smell it...
你聞不到
...because your nose already smells like that, but my nose doesn't.
因為你鼻子不好使，我的卻不一樣
Silence goes good with a lot of things. Ever try or is talking how you breathe?
沉默是金，你應該試著慢點說話
Just say you hate me. Don't take it out on the car.
煩我就直說，別等回車裏鬱悶
Let me enjoy this.
吃完再說
Whoa, enjoyment.
那就吃吧
So that's what enjoyment looks like on that face. I like that emotion.
看你表情就知道，我喜歡這情緒
I keep emotion out of it.
情緒和這無關
Out of what, K? Life?
和什麼無關，生活嗎？
You don't wanna run it by me?
你就不想讓我幫你一把？
-Let me know what you'll say? -Don't worry.
- 讓我看看你想說什麼？ - 別擔心
Oh, no, I'm worried. Very worried.
喔，不，我擔心，非常擔心
It's the man's eulogy. You have to show some feeling.
這可是悼詞，你必須要富有情感
That thing people do when they change their facial expression?
才能讓人們感動
I worked with Zed for 40 years. A hell of an agent.
我和澤德共事40年了，他很出色
And I have written a hell of a speech for him.
為了他我會寫下出色的悼詞
People will be moved.
大家會感動的
And now a few words from Agent K.
現在由K探員獻上幾句
I worked with Zed for over 40 years, and in all that time...
我和澤德共事40年
...he never invited me to dinner.
他從來不邀請我吃晚餐
He never asked me to his house to watch a game.
也從來沒邀請過我去他家看球賽
He never shared a single detail of his personal life.
從來不分享他個人生活的任何事
Yeah, he was weird.
是啊，他很古怪
Thank you.
謝謝
And now we will hear from our new chief, Agent O.
現在由新上任的領導O探員發言
Thank you, Agent K. That was very moving.
謝謝K探員，太感人了
-That was your eulogy? -He was a good man.
- 這就是你的悼詞？ - 他是個好人
Ladies, gentlemen, other life forms.
女士們，先生們及外星朋友們
When I told the Finucian Zyglot about Zed's passing...
當我把澤德去世的消息告訴 一位齊格羅星人時
...she said something that I'm going to repeat.
她說了一些話，接下來我會重複一遍
And I'm paraphrasing.
並釋義
That's just so Zed.
這就是澤德
Thank you.
謝謝
You lose something over here, Hondo?
有什麼不對勁嗎？老兄
Can you promise, if I go first, you'll do better than that at my funeral?
你能對我保證嗎，如果我先死了 你在葬禮上的悼詞一定要比這次好？
You know, something like:
比如：
"J was a friend.
J是我的朋友
Now there's a big part of me that's gone.
對我如此重要的人卻離我而去
Oh, J, all the things that I should have said...
噢，J，有些事還沒來得及告訴你
...except I was too old...
我是個老頭
...and craggy and surly...
脾氣壞，傲慢
...and just tight. I was too...
並且頑固
...tight.
很頑固
I'm gonna just miss your caramel-brown skin."
我很想念你性感黝黑的皮膚
I'll wing something.
我會現場發揮的
K, it's O. We have reports of several humans suffering from...
K，我是O，我們接到報案
...intestinal worms of alien origin.
有人類感染了外星蛔蟲
Thank you, O.
謝謝,O
How did you get to be like you?
你怎麼變成這樣了？
Something happened, K. What happened?
出什麼事了，K，發生什麼了？
You know how I live such a happy life?
你知道我沒什麼不開心的
How you live such a happy life?
沒什麼不開心的？
I don't ask questions I don't want to know the answer to.
我不該知道的從來不問
Jeffrey.
傑弗裏
Do I know you?
我認識你嗎？
Your services are legendary. So says your father, Obadiah.
你很有能力，你父親奧巴代亞告訴我的
You were in Lunar-Max.
你應該在月球監獄
There is no prison that can hold me.
沒有我逃不出的監獄
The device.
那個裝置
I'm going back in time to kill a man before he takes my arm.
我要盡快回到過去殺個人 在他奪走我手臂之前
So happy to see you. Mr. Wu get you your regular table?
見到你們很高興，這邊請
You no hungry?
不餓嗎？
Show us the tanks, Wu.
給我們看看水箱
Oh, sure, sure. You look. Very fresh.
當然，當然可以，你看看，很新鮮
Show us the tanks in the back.
讓我們看看後廚的水箱
So sorry. No speak English. You come back later, okay?
抱歉，聽不懂你們說的，晚點再來，好嗎？
Save the chop-socky bullshit for the tourists, Wu.
把這些屁話留給外地人吧
Hey, what you guys wanna bust my balls for, huh?
你們到底想幹什麼？
You don't have no balls.
你沒權知道
Man, you look like you come from the planet...
夥計，看起來你來自行星
...Damn.
該死
And Bob here is a clear violation of Health Ordinance 32:
鮑勃明顯違反了第32條衛生條例
Selling unlicensed extraterrestrial...
販賣未經許可的外星
...foodstuffs.
食品
That is an Earth fish.
那是地球上的魚類
Very traditional in China. You arrest me...
這在中國很常見，你要逮捕我的話
...that's a hate crime!
就是種族歧視！
It would be...
是啊
...if you were Chinese.
如果你是中國人的話
K, come on. I got larvae to feed.
K，拜託，我還要撫養幼蟲
Who is the Spiky Bulba for?
這尖刺魚是為誰準備的？
Nobody.
沒有誰
Who's it for?
為誰準備的？
I keep them in case!
我養著它而已！
-ln case what? -I don't know!
- 說不說？ - 我不知道
Anybody!
任何人！
All right, you slug.
好吧，你個臭蟲
Wu...
吳
...he and I are having issues right now, but you shouldn't suffer for that.
我和他之間有點問題，但不應該拿你出氣
Thank you, J.
謝謝，J
So if you don't like getting fish-slapped, keep to our agreement.
如果不想被魚扇耳光，得遵守協議
Earth people get Earth fish. Real Earth fish.
地球人吃地球魚，真正的地球魚類
On behalf of my pathetic self and worthless children, you stay.
為了我這個可憐的人和沒用的孩子 請您留下來吧
Allow me most honorable benefit of serving you favorite noodles, K?
能夠獻上您最喜歡的麵條我不勝榮幸 好嗎,K？
Don't nobody want your nasty-ass noodles.
沒人想吃你那噁心的麵條
You're a piece of shit, Wu.
你就是一坨屎，吳
Shrimp and bok choy.
放點蝦和白菜一起做
We're gonna be here for a while.
咱倆還得在這呆會
That was just mean.
真是的
What you did to Wu back there.
你在後廚都幹了些什麼
Snatched his skirt off.
扒掉他的圍裙
That's just disrespectful.
這太無禮了
I used to play a game with my dad:
以前我常和我爸玩個遊戲
What'll You Have For Your Last Meal.
你的最後一餐會吃什麼
You could do worse than this.
你可以做得比這更糟
I played a game with my dad...
我和老爸玩的遊戲
...called catch.
叫做「接球」
Except I'd throw the ball and it'd just hit the wall...
我把球扔出去，它只會打到牆上
...because he wasn't there.
因為我沒父親
Don't badmouth your old man.
別說你老子壞話
I'm not badmouthing him. I just didn't really know him.
不是說他壞話 我只是真的不知道他是什麼樣
It's not right.
這不對
Damn right it's not. A boy needs a father.
什麼對不對的，孩子需要父親
Table one hasn't ordered a thing. Table three...
一號桌還沒點餐
...just drank his fourth cup...
三號桌已經喝四杯
...of duck sauce.
鴨醬了
K, the crashed ship...
K，今天墜落的飛船
...from this morning was stolen from--
是從
Lunar-Max.
月球監獄
Boris the Animal.
禽獸鮑裏斯
How did you know?
你怎麼知道？
He has a taste for Spiky Bulba.
他一向愛吃尖刺魚
Give us a minute, chief.
給我們點時間，長官
We're in a situation.
有麻煩了
I take the Chloropod.
我對付Chloropod
You take the Tarantabee.
你對付Tarantabee
And the Hydronian over there.
和那邊的Hydronian
I'll take the kitchen.
然後我會搞定廚房裏的
Meet you on the street.
到街上會合
This is a very confusing time...
在我一生中
...in my life.
這可真夠亂套的
Hey.
嘿
Keep your mouth closed, keep your head down.
嘴閉上，頭低下
Hello, K.
哈嘍，K
Boris the Animal.
禽獸鮑裏斯
It's just Boris.
是「鮑裏斯」
You haven't changed very much. I see the arm I shot off is still shot off.
你沒怎麼變，還是一條胳膊
Yes, my arm.
是啊，我的胳膊
We've thought about that moment...
在過去的40年中
...every day for the last 40 years.
我無時無刻不在回想斷臂的瞬間
Well, that's just not living a full life.
你這輩子也就這樣了
I can promise you it will be longer than yours.
我敢保證我會活得比你長
Lonelier too. Since you're the last Boglodite standing.
如果你是最後一個伯格羅多星人 一樣會感到孤獨
We'll see about that.
走著瞧
But first, I want the pleasure of killing you.
但是首先，很高興可以親手殺了你
Yo, K.
唷，K
-Where the hell have you been? -Fishing.
- 你跑哪去了？ - 捕魚
You don't know it, K, but you're already dead.
你還不知道，K，其實你已經死了
You all right?
你沒事吧？
May I have everyone's attention, please?
請大家往我這邊看好嗎？
Thank you.
謝謝
You know how your kid won the goldfish in that little baggie...
你們知道孩子從集市弄了一袋金魚
...from the fair and you didn't want it in your house...
你們不想在家養它
...so you told your kid it ran away when you flushed it down the toilet?
所以就騙孩子說金魚跑了 然後就你們以為把它衝進馬桶便沒事了？
Well, this is what happens.
好吧，這就是你們幹的
Okay? See what I'm talking about? Don't lie to your kids.
如何？看到了嗎？別對孩子撒謊
Man, I am getting too old for this.
夥計，這些事我可干夠了
I can only imagine how you feel.
可以想像你是什麼感覺
Boris the Animal.
禽獸鮑裏斯
I put him away a long time ago. It's the worst mistake I ever made.
很久前我把它送到監獄 這是我犯過的最大錯誤
Why? Was he innocent?
為什麼？他是無辜的嗎？
Should have killed him.
應該殺了他
-Well, shit, let's go get him. -No.
- 該死，咱們去幹掉他吧 - 不
-Leave it alone.
- 不？ - 別管他
It's above your pay grade.
這不是你的職責
We have the same pay grade.
咱倆職責一樣
It has nothing to do with you. Mind your own business.
這與你無關，管好自己就行了
Okay, first of all, let's get a little bit of that bass out your voice.
好吧，首先，別總對我說教
Secondly, as long as Spikey Boy is running around, this is my business.
其次，只要那禽獸胡作非為，我就得管
You forget about Boris or my report will reflect...
如果你管這事我就向上級匯報
...that your conduct has been unbecoming.
你行為不端
Well, maybe my report is gonna reflect some shit too, K.
好啊，也許我也可以對你這麼做，K
-You are suspended for two weeks. -Bullshit.
- 你被停職兩周 - 胡說
Four weeks.
四周
How about I quit?
我退出怎麼樣？
There are things out there you don't need to know.
有些事你沒必要知道
That's not the lie you told me when you recruited me.
你雇我時可不是這麼說的
What up, pops?
還好嗎，大爺
-Lose your partner? -Yeah.
還好，搭檔沒來啊
Next shuttle to Afazumba...
距離穿梭至阿法尊巴星球
...Ieaving in 22 minutes.
還有22分鐘
Search...
搜索
...Boris the Animal.
禽獸鮑裏斯
Boris the Animal, Boglodite assassin.
禽獸鮑裏斯，伯格羅多星球刺客
Boglodites were a rogue alien race...
伯格羅多星人是很兇猛的外星種族
... that consumed all planets in their path.
所到之處片甲不留
Boris the Animal was the only suspect...
地球上的外星人謀殺案中
...in a series of alien murders on Earth.
唯一的嫌疑犯就是禽獸鮑裏斯
Incident report.
案件報告
Boris the Animal was convicted...
禽獸鮑裏斯在接下來的謀殺案中被判有罪
...for the following murders that occurred on July 15, 1969.
時間1969年7月15日
Murder number one: Coney Island, 10: 37 a.m. Roman the Fabulist.
謀殺罪名一： 康尼島，上午10:37，預言家羅曼
Murder number two: The Factory..
謀殺罪名二：工廠
Refine search.
精確搜索
Agent K.
K探員
Junior Agent K apprehended and arrested...
1969年7月16日
...Boris the Animal on July 16, 1969, at Cape Canaveral, Florida.
在佛羅里達州卡納維拉爾角 K探員逮捕了禽獸鮑裏斯
-Cape Canaveral.... -Agent K...
- 卡納維拉爾角
...received highest commendation for heroic action...
K探員的英勇事跡獲得了很高讚揚
...including implementation...
包括建立
...of the Arc Net Defense System...
天穹網防禦系統
... which protected the Earth from Boglodite invasion...
保護地球免遭伯格羅多星人入侵
...and led to the race's extinction.
最終人類勝利
Details.
細節
Access restricted.
訪問受限
Excuse me? Clearance level senior agent, class one. J.
對不起，清除高級探員權限 換為最高級別的J探員權限
Access denied.
拒絕訪問
What?
什麼？
So why this sudden interest in your partner's old exploits?
你怎麼突然對你搭檔的 陳年舊事感興趣了？
What happened between Boris and K?
鮑裏斯和K之間發生過什麼？
That's easy.
很簡單
K imprisoned Boris. He put up the Arc Net.
K囚禁了鮑裏斯，他建造了天穹網
He protected the Earth from the Boglodites.
他從伯格羅多星人手裏拯救了地球
He did his job.
他完成了他的使命
That's not what I'm asking.
這可不是我要問的
Cape Canaveral, what happened?
卡納維拉爾角，發生什麼了？
Something that changed him.
有些事改變了他
Leave it at that.
別談這些了
That's classified.
這是機密
A word of advice, Agent J.
奉勸一句，J探員
Don't ask questions you don't want to know the answer to.
不該知道的就別問
That's funny. That is exactly what K said.
有意思，K也是這麼說的
He's a very wise man.
他是個聰明人
Take the rest of the night off.
晚上好好休息
What?
怎麼？
Guess I owe you some answers, hoss.
我想我欠你一些答案，夥計
What, you're feeling chatty all of a sudden?
啥？你咋突然想說這些呢？
I can't talk right now. I've got secret cases of my own I'm working on.
現在不行，我在工作呢
I hate to tear you away from your video game.
真不想拆穿你在玩遊戲
All right, I'm hanging up.
好吧，我要掛了
You know the most destructive force in the universe?
知道宇宙中最具破壞性的力量是什麼嗎？
Sugar?
毒品？
Regret.
很遺憾
You don't have to wait. Just talk.
別繞了，直說吧
I promised you the secrets of the universe. Nothing more.
我向你保證過這秘密不能說，僅此而已
So there's secrets out there the universe don't know about?
還有什麼秘密我不能知道？
Mommy.
媽咪
Can I help you?
需要幫忙嗎？
K?
K呢？
5K.
5K嗎？（房間號）
I'm sorry, is that chocolate milk?
對不起，那是巧克力牛奶嗎？
Can l--? I'm so sorry. I don't know what....
我能…？對不起，我不知道怎麼了…
Mommy, the president is drinking...
媽咪，奧巴馬搶我的
...my milk.
- 牛奶喝 - 嗯
I'm sorry.
對不起
He didn't say please.
他還沒問我同不同意呢
-K get in yet? -Who?
- K來了嗎？ - 誰？
You new?
你新來的？
Very funny, Agent J.
真有意思，J探員
J, everything you told me yesterday, you were right as rain.
J，昨天你跟我說的那些，真是及時雨啊
-Thank God for that 10-hour stakeout. -Who are you?
- 感謝上帝給了這10小時的監視 - 你是誰？
Exactly. I feel like a whole new man today.
沒錯，今天我覺得自己煥然一新
Like this great weight has been lifted. I've had anger issues my entire life...
進步很快，之前總是對身邊的一切感到不滿
...but now I see I was mad at myself. And my stepmom.
但現在只對自己和繼母不滿
Sir, I'm gonna need you to stop talking.
先生，別說了好嗎
It's like I closed this emotional window.
這就像我關閉了情感之窗
But I threw a brick through that window.
但又打破了它
Thank you for handing me that brick, J.
多謝你的引導，J
Whoever you are, give me five feet or I'll pluck you in your throat.
不管你是誰，離我遠點 否則我扯下你的喉嚨
I'm gonna go to the little Men's-in-Black room...
好吧，我得去黑衣人那了
...then we'll go find those morons from Pox Ethera. Lunch is on me.
然後去找博伊希拉星球的蠢貨 午飯我請
Who was that?
那是誰？
Double A? Your partner.
扇你屁股那位？你搭檔
I need you to go get me some chocolate milk, all right?
你給我拿杯巧克力牛奶，好嗎？
Just a really big glass. Have you seen K?
大杯的，你看到K了嗎？
Did he call in sick or anything?
他請病假了還是怎麼了？
Who's K?
誰是K？
All right, all right, go ahead, go ahead.
好吧，好吧，跟我扯吧
K!
K！你在哪？
All right.
好吧
You got me.
你贏了
I'll give it to you. It's funny, very elaborate.
不得不說，很有趣，煞費苦心啊
Oh, and all of you, fantastic performances.
你們大家，演得真不錯
You waited 14 years to develop a sense of humor...
都14年了才知道你們這麼幽默
...but this is a good one.
這個很不錯
But I need you to come out here now...
K，現在你得出來了
...because I'm starting to get a little pissed off.
因為我已經有點不太高興了
Agent J, would you mind keeping your voice down...
J探員，介意小點聲說話嗎
...and telling me who you're looking for?
你想找誰？
I'm looking for K.
我在找K
Who is K?
誰是K？
I mean, who is he to you?
我是問，他到底誰是？
My partner.
我搭檔
Older gentleman, 110...
110歲的老頭子
...maybe 111 years old.
也許111了
Sort of a surly, Elvis thing happening with him. He smiles like this.
有點傲慢，像貓王一樣，他是這麼笑的
Seen him around?
看見過嗎？
I'll take you to K.
我帶你去見他
Thank you.
謝謝
-What is that supposed to be? -That's K.
- 這是什麼？ - 是K
He's been dead for over 40 years.
他已經去世40多年了
Okay, see, the prerequisite for a joke is that it be funny.
好吧，看得出來 如果這是笑話的話確實很有趣
It's never been funny.
沒開玩笑
Computer, Agent K and Boris the Animal.
電腦，K探員和禽獸鮑裏斯
Men in Black incident report, July, 1969.
黑衣人事件報告，1969年7月
Location, Cape Canaveral.
地點：卡納維拉爾角
Perpetrator Boris the Animal escaped and fled Earth.
罪犯禽獸鮑裏斯逃往地球
Assumed to have returned to planet Boglodotia 20 light-years away.
假設返回伯格羅多星球需20光年
Agent K pronounced dead at scene. Awarded posthumous commendation...
K探員在這次事件中宣告死亡 對於他拯救人類的英勇行為
...for action which prevented greater loss of human life.
當局予以表彰
That's not what happened.
這不可能
I looked at this report. K put Boris away--
我看過這篇報告 K把鮑裏斯囚禁起來
-Agent K is dead. -Well, I just talked to him last night.
- K探員已經死了 - 昨晚我還跟他通話來著
-You are imagining. -I'm not.
- 都是你在想像而已 - 才不是
-I need a psych team up here. -Yes, ma'am.
- 我需要心理醫生到這來 - 好的，女士
Aqua Velva aftershave. I didn't imagine that.
他用Aqua Velva須後水，這不是想像
Every stakeout, endless hours of cowboy music.
每次監視行動，連續幾小時都是牛仔音樂
Every morning with his coffee...
每天早上喝咖啡，他總是說
And I was supposed to say, "What do you expect?
然後我說「什麼樣才和你口味？
-lt was ground this morning." -"This morning."
這可是早上現磨的咖啡」
How do you know that?
你怎麼知道的？
Chocolate milk, sir?
巧克力牛奶，先生？
Where you been, man? It was like an hour ago.
你去哪了，夥計？ 這都一小時了
Wait.
等下
How long have you been craving chocolatized dairy products?
你喜歡巧克力乳製品多久了？
Just today.
今天才開始
Are you experiencing headaches? Dizziness?
有頭痛，頭暈
Loss of balance?
- 失去平衡 - 嗯哼
Agitation? Depression?
煩躁，抑鬱的感覺嗎？
Hell, yeah.
是啊，有
Two possibilities. One is you've been bitten...
兩種可能，一種是你被
...by a Hovartian brain tick...
哈瓦星球的腦蜱蟲咬了
...and could die in horrible agony at any moment.
隨時都可能痛苦掙扎的死去
Damn it. It's not the tick.
該死，不是蜱蟲
"Damn it, it's not the tick"?
該死，不是蜱蟲？
It's something worse than the tick?
比蜱蟲還糟？
Your obsession with chocolate milk indicates...
你對巧克力牛奶的癡迷表明
...that you might be involved in a temporal fracture.
你可能參與過某個短時間的時空穿梭
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不明白你在說什麼
Chocolate milk relieves temporal-fracture headaches.
巧克力牛奶可以去除因時空穿梭導致的頭痛
What's a temporal fracture?
時空穿梭是什麼？
A break in the timeline.
穿越到任意時間點
Don't know what you mean.
還是不明白你的意思
Time travel! Time travel.
時間旅行！時間旅行
There's no such thing as time travel.
根本不存在時間旅行
-Well, there is. -No.
- 這個可以有 - 這個真沒有
There's not.
沒有
Because if there were...
因為如果有的話
...a class-one senior agent such as myself...
像我這類頂級探員
...would have been aware of it, wouldn't he have?
應該有權知道，難道他不是嗎？
Were it not classified and way above his pay grade.
這根本不是機密，只是他越權辦事
You know, I need a raise.
你知道我想要什麼
There was one man, scumbag, Obadiah Price.
有個卑鄙的傢伙 奧巴代亞·普賴斯
He figured it out, we busted him, we made time travel illegal...
他發明的，我們開除了他 穿越宇宙這技術對我們來說是違法的
...throughout the universe and he is serving life on Lunar-Max.
他被判終生監禁在月球監獄
No-- That's where Boris was locked up.
鮑裏斯也關在那
...he could seriously change the course of history.
他一定會改寫歷史
Inbound hostile warships entering solar system.
敵方戰艦已進入太陽系
Boglodite markings and language detected.
檢測到伯格羅多種族信息
Boglodite. Boris is a Boglodite, but they're extinct.
伯格羅多，鮑裏斯是伯格羅多星人 但他們已經滅絕了
Apparently not.
顯然沒有
Catastrophic Earth attack imminent.
地球即將遭受災難性打擊
Put up the Arc Net.
啟用天穹網
-The what? -The Arc Net. The defense system.
- 什麼？ - 天穹網，防禦系統
K got it for the Boglodites.
K發明的，為了防止伯格羅多星人入侵
There is no K.
K早就不在了
He's been dead for over 40 years.
他已經去世40多年了
No K. No defense system.
他不在就沒有防禦系統
Boris jumped back and killed him.
鮑裏斯回到過去殺了他
If you wanna save the world, stop that from happening.
如果你想拯救世界，從一開始就要阻止他
You have to find Jeffrey Price. He's Obadiah's son.
你去找傑弗裏·普賴斯 他是奧巴代亞的兒子
Let's hope the little squirt hasn't skipped town.
希望這小子能幫上忙
-Good luck, J! -This planet's toast.
- 祝你好運，J！ - 這是地球的臨別祝詞，哈哈哈
How can I help you? We're having an amazing sale...
需要點什麼？我這電池
...on batteries.
賣的很不錯
Okay, we got other stuff, like headphones, adapters or--
哇哦，好吧，我還有別的東西 耳機，充電器什麼的
You helped Boris the Animal time jump.
你幫助禽獸鮑裏斯時空穿梭
Okay, I had to. That dude's a freak.
是，我必須得做，那傢伙是個怪物
He killed my partner.
他殺了我搭檔
I want to know when and where you sent him.
我想知道他傳送的時間地點
What, you think I keep, like, a logbook?
我會告訴你全記在本子裏了嗎？
Target vector, July 16...
目標方位，1969年7月16日
-...1969. -All right.
好吧
That's a real bummer about your buddy.
你朋友真是個無賴
I'm sure he was a great guy.
我知道他很棒
But in terms of the space-time continuum...
但根據時間連續體來說
...your friend was a little blip on the historical radar!
你朋友在歷史上簡直不值一提
That's a big blip.
出大麻煩了
-Okay. What's the plan? -You're gonna send me...
- 好吧，我該怎麼辦？ - 你把我送回
...back to July 15th, 1969.
1969年7月15日
No, that's a stupid plan, because I sent Boris to July 16th.
不，這不對，因為我把鮑裏斯送到7月16日
I'm not worried about that one. I'll kill the younger Boris...
這不是我擔心的 我要在鮑裏斯現身前
...before the older one shows.
殺了年輕時的他
That way, neither of them will even exist.
那樣的話，他們兩個都得消失
That's why you get to wear the black suit.
這就是你為什麼穿黑制服
No?
不是嗎？
You're gonna leave me hanging? Okay.
咱倆不撞一下嗎？好吧
Oh, I just thought of something. Even back then...
喔，我想起來了
...New York was like a big-ish city.
那年代紐約又大又亂
So how are you gonna really find him?
你打算怎麼找到他？
On July 15th, Boris killed an alien, Roman the Fabulist, at Coney lsland.
7月15日，鮑裏斯在康尼島殺了一名 叫做預言家羅曼的外星人
You're gonna get there first and be waiting?
你準備先到那等他出現？
Dude, they should give you two black suits.
夥計，他們應該給你兩套黑制服
My man, for real?
老弟，能認真點嗎？
Oh, right.
好吧
Sorry.
對不起
This...
這才是
...is the real deal. Time-jump gear.
真傢伙，時空穿梭裝置
Very rare, very old.
非常稀有，有年頭了
But first, we gotta get high.
但首先，咱們得「嗨」一下
Hey. No.
嘿，不
No. No, I mean, really high.
不是，我是說到很高的地方 （high有多重意思）
Okay.
好的
-You know the rules of time jumps? -Give me the short version.
- 知道時空穿梭的規則嗎？ - 長話短說
Okay. You wanna save your partner, word of advice:
想救你搭檔，建議：
Stay away from him.
離他遠點
Yeah, got it. Stay away from K. Just kill Boris.
記住了嗎，離K遠點，殺了鮑裏斯就行
Now, take these.
現在，拿上這個
It gets pretty windy on the way down.
掉下去時會獲得足夠的風速
The way down?
掉下去？
With eyes tearing up, it's hard to read the dial.
如果你哭的話，就看不到刻度盤了
Plus, it helps you look like a real time traveler, which is cool.
再說，他使你看起來更像時間旅行者 這酷斃了
I am not jumping off of this building!
我才不要從這跳下去！
Time jump.
不跳就沒戲
Okay, now...
好了，現在
...I gotta set this thing...
我設置一下
...to the 15th.
到15日
...right-ish.
沒錯
Now...
現在
...all you gotta do is jump.
就差你一跳了
Hey, hey, stop. Stop it.
嘿，別，別拍我
When you're moving fast enough...
當你下落速度足夠快時
...that circle is gonna fill up with some sort of green time-travel liquid...
圓圈內會充滿綠色液體
...and it's gonna glow really bright.
發出奪目的亮光
As soon as that happens, break that blue laser line...
然後你盡快用拇指劃過藍色激光線
...with your thumb to complete the circuit.
來完成這次旅行
At this height, that should be....
這個高度，應該是…
Let's see, mass of Earth and 30-something feet per minute....
我算算，地球質量和每分鐘30英尺左右
It's 32 feet per second. Per second.
每秒32英尺，每秒！
That sounds right-ish.
你說得對
So that would be, I guess, about two feet off the ground.
我想應該是…，大約離地面兩英尺
I break the laser line?
劃過激光線嗎？
No, don't break it!
不，別碰它！
-No, when I'm fast enough! -Sounds good!
- 那什麼時候才算快！ - 聽起來不錯
Do I break the laser line or do I not break the laser line?
劃過激光線到底有沒有用？
Do not lose that time device...
別把這設備弄丟了
...or you will be stuck in 1969!
否則你就得一直呆在1969年了！
It wasn't the best time for your people.
對你來說可不是什麼好時候
I'm just saying. It's, like, a lot cooler now.
只是說說，讓你冷靜一下
How will I know if it works?
我怎麼知道這是否有用？
You'll either know...
非生
...or you won't.
即死
You must really love this guy to do this.
你一定很喜歡這傢伙才會這麼做
Oh, wait. How come I remember K, but nobody else does?
等等，為什麼只有我記得K？ 其他人都忘了
-That means you were there! -I was where?
- 那說明當時你在那 - 在哪？
If you survive, you gotta come back and tell me everything.
如果你活著回來，一定跟我好好講講
Where was l?
在哪？
You gotta go!
你得跳了！
Just go, go, go!
快跳，快！
Oh, no!
哦，不！
Come on!
快啊！
-My man, what's today? -Tuesday.
- 老兄，今天星期幾 - 星期三
-The date? -The 15th.
- 幾號？ - 15號
-Of? -July.
- 哪月？ - 7月
-Dog, the year. -1969.
- 年份呢 - 1969年
Thank you.
謝謝
Look at me like I'm crazy.
我不會以為我瘋了吧
Far out.
太棒了
Jerry rocked Haight-Ashbury like you wouldn't believe.
你不會相信的 傑瑞在嬉皮士的地盤嗨翻了
Okay, we're here.
好的，我們到了
-Happy? -You're such a pill, Fred.
- 高興嗎？ - 你真令人討厭，佛瑞德
-Get us checked in. -Yeah, yeah.
- 去辦入住手續 - 知道了
Hey. Hey, do me a favor, all right?
嘿，幫個忙，好嗎？
-Be careful with the luggage. -Absolutely, sir.
- 拿行李時小心點 - 一定會的，先生
I paid a lot of money for that luggage.
這行李箱貴著呢
-We'll take good care-- -Last time, it got scuffed up.
- 我們會照看好的 - 還有別磨壞了
Here you go, sir. Just call down when you need it.
給你，先生 如果需要服務就叫我
There's more in the trunk.
後備箱還有行李
Yeah, it'll be in your room, sir. Just go in.
知道了，會安排妥當的，先生。請進去吧
Excuse me. Excuse me, who is that? Who are you?
對不起，打擾一下，那是誰？
Let's go!
快走啊！
Far out, man!
不錯啊，夥計！
If you want to keep that, I wouldn't.
如果你再這樣我就不客氣了
Make love, not war.
笑一個別生氣
I prefer to do both.
不用你告訴我該怎麼做
How are you, officers? What can I do you for?
警官，你好嗎？ 我能為你做點什麼？
Well, look at this. Power windows, power seats.
看吶，電動車窗和密封條
-I'll bet you it cost 6 grand. -Yeah.
我打賭這車得6千美元
Yes, and it has a roof, but it's hidden.
是啊，這車還有個隱藏式頂棚
Hey, what kind of work do you do?
嘿，你是做什麼的？
An individual of your...
像你這種膚色的人
...particular ethnic persuasion?
能買得起這種車嗎？
Yes. Starting forward for the Detroit Darkies.
是啊，我是底特律黑人隊的前鋒
-Where'd you get the car? -And the suit?
車和制服哪來的？
I stole them both. Car from your wife...
從你們那偷的，車是你老婆的
...suit from your grandmother.
制服是你奶奶的
Hey.
嘿
What do we have here? Concealed weapon?
這是什麼？武器嗎？
Hey, it's his grandmother's suit.
嘿，這可是他奶奶的制服
-Hey, what's this? -Probably drugs.
- 嘿，這是什麼？ - 可能是毒品
I have rights and I demand to see my lawyer...
在你們按旁邊的按鈕前
...before you press that small button on the side firmly.
我有權見我的律師
Press it.
按一下試試
That, gentlemen, is a standard-issue neuralyzer.
先生們，這就是記憶消除器的功能
You're not gonna remember that.
你們不會記得了
And just because you see a black man driving a nice car...
因為當你們看見一個黑人開著豪車
...does not mean it's stolen.
並不意味著就是偷的
I stole that one. But not because I'm black.
這輛是偷的，但不是因為我是黑人
I'll be done with the car in a minute!
這車我還得用一會
Just find it and take it back to the jerk at the Roosevelt Hotel.
你們找到後還給羅斯福酒店那個蠢貨
Where is the Archanan?
阿查南星人在哪？
You are too late.
你太晚了
He is going to give the humans...
他已經把天穹網
...the Arc Net.
交給人類了
Let's agree to disagree.
咱們走著瞧
We'll take it from here.
這事我們負責
K?
K，是你嗎？
K! K!
K！真是你
Dad, I'm on Earth.
爸，我在地球呢
I need bail.
來保釋我
Will the owner of a blue warp-speed cruiser...
藍色變形飛船的主人
...please report to the front desk.
請到前台報道
You need to turn the electricity down on that damn thing.
你應該把那該死的東西電量調低點
Can't taste my fricking tongue, K.
我舌頭都麻了，K
How do you know my name?
你怎麼知道我名字？
What? Because I called you "K"?
什麼？因為我叫你K？
No, I call everybody K.
不，我管每個人都叫K
It's kind of my thing.
我就這樣
What up, K?
是吧，K？
All right, I sort of--
好吧，有點…
Yeah, that's kind of my thing. I just-- Some people like it.
我就是這樣子，只是… 有人喜歡這樣
Most people.
很多人
Now that I know what you look like...
現在我知道你撒謊的時候
...when you're lying, show me...
是什麼樣了，時候讓我看看
...what you look like when you're telling the truth?
你說實話的樣子吧？
I won those at Coney lsland on the ring toss.
這些是我在康尼島玩套圈贏的
I won a stuffed bear once, but never one of these.
曾經我贏過一隻玩具熊 這些東西倒是沒見過
Must be good, slick.
你技術一定很不錯，滑頭
All right, sir, I was minding my own business.
好吧，先生，能贏到什麼這是我的事
I was waiting for my girl, who, by the way...
我在等我朋友，順便說下
...is probably worried sick looking for me right now.
我不見了她現在一定擔心得要命
So I just need my things and I need to get back to her.
所以我得拿回我的東西回去見她
What's her name?
她叫什麼？
Your gal, what's her name?
你女朋友，她叫什麼？
Schtaron?
史特瑞恩？
I bet Schtaron likes that suit of yours.
我打賭史特瑞恩就是你的制服，對吧？
What, it's a crime to wear a black suit?
什麼，穿黑制服犯法嗎？
All right, listen. I haven't done anything wrong.
好吧，聽著，我沒做錯什麼
And I need to get out of here. I cannot be with you.
我要離開這，不想和你再談了
Terribly sorry. X is frightfully upset about the whole Coney lsland incident.
非常抱歉，因為康尼島的事X快崩潰了
Thanks for the heads-up.
多謝提醒
Oh, man, this coffee tastes like dirt.
哦，夥計，這咖啡味道可不怎麼樣
-What do you expect? It was-- -Just ground this morning.
- 什麼樣才和你口味？這可是 - 早上現磨的咖啡
O?
你是O？
No, I call ladies "O."
不，我稱女士為O
To me, O is feminine, K is masculine.
對我來說，O是女性，K是男性
You know, I see a couple, I'm like, "O-K."
這就好比我喜歡的詞「O-K」
What a mess. Any casualties?
一團糟，有傷亡報告嗎？
Yes, Roman the Fabulist.
是的，預言家羅曼
Any human casualties?
人類有傷亡嗎？
No, sir.
沒有，先生
Who the hell is this?
這傢伙是誰？
Look, I was--
我是…
-Stray human caught in the net. -Code 43 him and throw him back.
- 一個迷路的 - 送到43號房間，沒事就放他走
You're late for a meeting with the Viagrans.
您該去參加 與維格安星人的會議了
They have a revolutionary new pill.
他們發明了一種革命性的新藥物
It's really....
真的是…
Okay, slick.
好了，滑頭
I was waiting for my girl.
我在等我的女友
Schtaron.
史特瑞恩
Yes, she's Greek.
沒錯，希臘人
Okay. Just one last thing. An eye exam.
好吧，最後一件事，眼科檢查
That's not an eye exam, K. That's a big-ass neuralyzer!
這根本不是眼科檢查，K 這是他媽的大號記憶消除器
You have a lot of information for a fella who doesn't know anything.
你看著傻呼呼的，知道的還不少
I see what you're saying.
我都明白
You know, K, we need to hold up a second.
哇哦，你知道的,K 咱等會行嗎
K!
K！
Let's get this bite guard in here.
先戴上牙套
Hey, back up, back up.
滾開，滾開
K, listen, I think we got off on the wrong foot, all right?
K,聽著，咱們不該以這種方式開頭，對嗎？
So let's just stop for a second and talk.
咱們停下來談談吧
Don't put me in here, K!
別讓我進去，K！
Too late, hoss.
太晚了，種馬
K, no, listen to me. I can help you with this case!
K，不，聽我說 我能幫你擺脫困境！
K!
K！
I'm doing the truth face! You're missing it!
這次是說真的！看我表情就知道了！
I'll just use my imagination.
我想像一下就行了
K, the killer...
K,你在找的殺手
...you're looking for, I'm after the same guy. A Boglodite.
我也在找他，是伯格羅多星人
His name is Boris.
他叫鮑裏斯
Ship has sailed, amigo.
設備已啟動，朋友
If we don't get him, there'll be two.
如果咱們抓不到他，就會有兩個他
You had my undivided attention.
我沒騙你
One will have one arm...
一個有一隻胳膊
...and one's gonna have two. K!
一個有兩隻胳膊
Listen to me!
聽我說！
If you erase me...
如果你毀掉我的記憶
...you erase the world!
就等於毀掉世界！
Fifteen seconds...
還有15秒
...to neuralyzation. Fourteen.
執行記憶刪除程序，14秒
Thirteen. Twelve.
13秒，12秒
Eleven. Ten. Nine.
11秒，10秒，9秒
When you see Boris tomorrow, K, kill him. Do not arrest him, kill him!
當你明天看到鮑裏斯時，殺了他 別抓他，直接殺了他！
Four. Three. Two.
4秒，3秒，2秒
Is this thing off? Hey, I don't think it's all the way off, K!
這東西關了嗎？還沒完全關閉吧？
It's whirring and buzzing.
還在嗡嗡響呢
I don't know if I don't know nothing.
我是不是什麼都不知道了
I knew Roman.
我認識羅曼
His wife cooked me dinner once. While it was not pleasant...
曾經吃過他妻子做的晚餐 雖然味道不怎麼樣
...he was my friend.
但他是我朋友
Last chance, who are you and what do you know?
最後一次機會，你是誰你想幹什麼？
I'm an agent...
我是來自未來的MIB探員
...from the future. We're partners.
咱們倆是搭檔
In 25 years, you'll recruit me...
25年後你會雇我
...and 14 years after that, the guy you didn't let me kill today...
再等14年，今天你阻止我要殺的那傢伙
...escapes from prison, jumps to the past...
從監獄裏逃出來，回到過去
...and unleashes an invasion of Earth. We got about 19 hours to kill him...
並且開始時入侵地球 我們還有19小時可以殺了他
...so, really, we need to go right now.
所以咱們現在就得行動
All right.
好吧
So that's the story you believe.
所以你相信我說的故事了
That one was the truth.
我相信是真的
Wasn't the whole truth, but it'll do for now.
雖然不一定都是真的 但可以滿足目前需要
What are you talking about? Of course it's the whole truth.
你以為呢？當然都是真的
The problem with a lie is once you start lying you put yourself....
咱們之間唯一的謊言就是你曾經…
Agent K.
K探員
What's he still doing here?
他還在這幹什麼？
I might have cooked him too long. Thought I'd walk him out.
我審了他很久，該讓他回去了
I put my pants on.
咱倆是好基友
Okay, future man, where to?
未來之人，咱去哪？
I don't know.
我不知道
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
Go wherever you went last time.
我不知道，去你最後到的地方？
I haven't been here. I didn't tell you where I went?
難道我沒告訴你我要去哪嗎？
No. I mean, we don't really talk.
沒，我是說，咱倆根本就沒怎麼談過
What kind of partners sit in a car every day for 14 years and don't talk?
什麼樣的搭檔才能 相處14年都沒怎麼說過話
Exactly. And this is the type of problem it causes.
沒錯，這就是問題所在
It's dysfunctional.
這可不好
All right, sport, you better get useful real quick or you go back in room 43.
好吧，你最好現在就能證明自己的能力 否則就給我回43號房間裏呆著
Man....
夥計…
There was something in the file about a factory.
還有個什麼關於工廠的
Something happened at a factory.
在工廠有事發生
Hey, look, man, you can put your Jedi Knight on me all you want.
老兄，你怎麼瞪我都沒用
That's all I got.
這就是我知道的
That spark something?
提醒你什麼了？
Roman had this on his person when he was murdered.
羅曼死的時候身上帶著這個
No, it's a clue.
不，這是線索
He didn't smoke.
他不抽煙
You lose something over here, Hondo?
有什麼不對勁嗎？老兄
No.
沒有
Hey, man, how old are you?
你多大了？
Twenty-nine.
29歲
I'm starting to understand why we don't talk.
貌似我知道為啥咱倆沒話說了
-How well do you know this place? -I know its reputation.
- 你怎麼知道這地方？ - 名氣大
I don't like it. I hate going in blind. I'm gonna need my gun.
我不喜歡盲目做事，我需要我的槍
Sure thing, slick.
可以，滑頭
K! Wait, no, I gotta go in with you!
K，等等，別，我得和你一起去！
You sit tight. I'll be fine.
你別動就好，我去搞定
Wait, no! No!
等等，別！別去！
K!
K！
K, don't go in by yourself!
K，別自己去！
Hi, fellas.
嗨，夥計們
Need to see the boss.
見你們老闆
He's busy.
他忙著呢
Well, I'm gonna just take a look around.
好吧，那我隨便逛逛
Looks like we have ourselves a standoff.
貌似打個平手
Looks that way.
應該是
-Still keep the key under the ashtray. -Lucky guess.
- 還把鑰匙放煙灰缸底下 - 算你走運
Now, where were we?
這是什麼地方？
I was about to tell you to screw off.
把我頭擰下來也不會告訴你們
Hey, slick, you bowl in the future?
滑頭，保齡球玩的如何？
MiB league champ, three years running.
連續3年MIB聯賽冠軍
Well, let's see it.
好吧，讓我瞧瞧
...establishment and rip my head off!
擰下我的頭！
My man, we don't have a lot of time. You really need to tell him something.
夥計，你時日不多了，跟他說實話吧
I'll tell him this!
說個屌！
All right, your head.
好吧，你選的
Wait. Hey, if you do this, I am gonna hunt you down...
等等，嘿，如果你這麼干 我不會放過你的
...and make sure you...
肯定讓你
...walk funny for the rest...
一輩子
...of your miserable last days on Earth!
吃不了兜著走
Tough spare, slick.
- 看你剩這兩個，滑頭 - 上帝！
You messed with the wrong head!
你們惹錯人了！
-His head's a little.... -You gonna tell us...
他頭有點…
...where Dom is?
快說他在哪
I'll kill you both. I'll kill both of youse!
我要殺了你們，你們倆死定了！
Your hook's a little off. Want me to clean her?
球上有汗水太滑了吧 用我幫你清理下嗎？
-Sure thing. -No, no, no.
- 好啊 - 別，別，別
Come on, I just cleaned the bathroom with this thing!
拜託，早上我用這個洗過頭了
No cleaning! No cleaning!
別洗了！別洗了！
Okay! Okay, all right! All right, he's in the back.
行了！行了！夠了，他在後面
But he's not gonna talk to Men in Black scum like you.
但他不會和你這種黑衣人渣談的
Now give me back my head.
現在把我頭放回去
K, I call this one "Low Hanging Fruit."
K，我管這叫「勝利在望」
That ain't a finger hole...
這可不是手指孔
...you sick bastard!
你個王八蛋！嗷！
I'll pop your head off...
我會以其人之道
...and see how you like it.
還治其人之身
I'm gonna kill both of you!
我要殺了你們！
I'm gonna kill the both of youse!
你們死定了！
I'll kill you both!
我會殺了你們的
-Well, we're on the right track. -Just the wrong train.
咱們來對地方了，就是時機不適合
If he had any secrets...
如果他有什麼秘密
...I'm guessing he spilled them.
估計已經招了
A smart man figures out what victims have in common.
聰明人會多謀善斷
A smart man would.
沒錯
That's a big-ass phone.
那是大哥大嗎
-Don't put that up to your head. -Agent O.
- 這東西輻射可不小 - O探員
How's your day been, Agent K?
今天進展如何，K探員？
Fair to middling.
馬馬虎虎
How are things going?
你怎麼樣？
Very. good, thank you.
還不錯，謝謝
Hey, you saw her like an hour ago.
一小時前你們不見過面嗎
I need cleanup and containment at Cosmic Lanes.
我在宇宙保齡球館 派人來清理隔離現場
Listen, I got a dead Parlaxian.
我這有一個帕萊先星人受害者
Now Roman was a Byvoid, correct me if I'm wrong...
如果沒猜錯的話，羅曼是巴沃爾德星人
-...from the same planetary grouping? -A system in the Triangulum Galaxy...
這兩個星球屬同一星系，都是三角星座裏的
...wiped out by Boglodites.
並且都讓伯格羅多星人佔領了
Wasn't the third planet--?
第三個星球呢？
-Glamouria? -Glamouria.
- Glamouria星球？ - Glamouria星球 （真實存在的《魅力》雜誌美國版）
Thank you, Miss O.
謝謝，O小姐
I know where Boris is headed to next.
我知道鮑裏斯接下來會去哪
You were close, slick. It's not a factory, it's the Factory.
你說得沒錯，滑頭 不過不是工廠，是時尚派對
Look, if Boris turns out to be here, I'm gonna kill him...
如果鮑裏斯來著，我會殺了他的
-...I need my gun. -No deal.
- 把槍給我 - 沒門
I've been an agent for 14 years.
我做了14年探員
Which means I'm the senior agent on this case. Now, I hate to pull rank...
作為高級探員經驗比你豐富 現在我不想擺架子
...but I am instructing my junior agent...
但我必須要求你這個初級探員
...that's you, to give me my gun right now. That's an order.
把槍還給我，馬上！這是命令
No, no, no, space gun.
不，不，不，太空槍
You're welcome.
不客氣
I didn't say thank you.
我沒說謝謝
For such an ungainly species, they've thrived on Earth.
這麼難看的物種，來地球幹什麼
I was an agent for three years...
當了3年探員
...before I realized all models were aliens.
才知道所有模特都是外星人
Found out the hard way.
算是歷盡艱險
Password?
口令?
Hey, look, funky '60s dude, we don't have a lot of time.
60年代的時髦小伙 咱可沒時間跟你耗著
Janis Joplin.
詹尼斯·喬普林
Is there anybody here who's not an alien?
這裏全是外星人吧？
Very nice.
真不錯
Blink. That's good.
眨眼，太好了
Look in the camera.
往攝像機這邊看
Is that Andy Warhol?
那是安迪·沃霍爾？ （20世紀藝術界知名人士）
Yep.
是他
Excuse me, Mr. Warhol, could we have a minute?
打擾一下，沃霍爾先生，有時間嗎？
Now is not a good time. This is a be-in.
現在可不是時候，我這忙著呢
Just a few...
有幾個
...questions.
問題想問你
No questions. No answers.
我不會回答的
Just being.
我還有事
We have an urgent matter to discuss with you...
我們有急事要跟你談下
...regarding one of your party guests.
關於這次派對上的一個客人
Why don't you come back...
為什麼你們不下周再來
...next week, after the happening...
等事情
...has happened.
結束的時候
Sorry, Mr. Warhol. You like talking slow. We got stuff to do.
抱歉，沃霍爾先生 你語速太慢，時間不等人
I've got a planet to save.
我還得拯救地球呢
You're distressing. Everything...
你真無禮
...about you upsets me.
令我很不舒服
Damn it, K! Are you trying to blow my cover?
該死，K！你想讓我暴露身份嗎？
Agent W, your cover is safe.
W探員，沒事的
Whoa, Andy Warhol is one of us?
安迪·沃霍爾是自己人？
Safe?
沒事？
You out of your mind? I'm so out of ideas...
你瘋了嗎？我都沒招了
...I'm painting cans and bananas for chrissakes.
只能畫畫罐頭和香蕉
Actually, Mr. Warhol, I gotta tell you, I love your work.
實際上，沃霍爾先生 我得告訴你我喜歡你的工作
Oh, thank you.
謝謝
Who's the dumb-ass?
那蠢驢是誰？
-Dumb-ass. -Say it again.
- 什麼，蠢驢嗎？ - 你敢再說一遍
-Want me to? -I dare you.
- 你想聽？ - 我打賭你不敢
Dumb-ass.
蠢驢
-Agents. -I have no problem...
- 兩位特工 - 和安迪·沃霍爾相比
...pimp-slapping the shiznit out of Andy Warhol.
你就是一坨屎
What?
什麼？
Why are you looking at me?
看我幹什麼？
Oh, all right. You know what? Agent K...
好吧，你知道嗎？K探員
...you see what information you can get from Agent W...
你跟W探員慢慢嘮吧
...and I'll go case the perimeter.
我到外面看看
-That work for everybody? -Go do that.
- 這樣行了吧？ - 幹你的活去吧
-How about that? -Oh, cute.
- 這個如何？ - 小屁孩
-Okay. -Very nice.
- 滿意了 - 很好
Someone forget his nap?
某人不覺得自己很幼稚嗎？
Hey, how you doing?
嘿，你好嗎？
Chilling.
不好
Who's that guy?
那傢伙是誰？
Don't tell me he's your new partner.
別告訴我他是你的新搭檔
Actually, he's my old partner. He traveled back from the future--
實際上他是我的老搭檔，他來自未來…
Stop, don't tell me. I don't want to know.
停，別說了，我不想知道
Andy, Yoko's here.
安迪，洋子來了
Yoko's here.
洋子來了，額…
Tell her that I'm filming this man eating a hamburger.
告訴她我在為這人拍吃漢堡的戲
It's transcendent.
這棒極了
All right, now the pickle.
好吧，該換泡菜了
What are you doing on my turf?
你在我地盤幹什麼？
Tracking a killer. Boglodite.
追蹤一個殺手，伯格羅多星人
We believe he's gonna hit here next, a Glamourian.
我們認為他會來這找一個格羅莫尼亞星人
Glamourian? Right solar system, wrong planet.
格羅莫尼亞？星系沒錯，但星球不對
He's gotta be after the Archanan.
他的目標是Archanan
Archanans are extinct.
Archanan已經滅絕了
Apparently not. One washed ashore last week.
顯然沒有，上周海灘出現一個
The whole Roswell circuit's all abuzz about it.
整個羅斯威爾都在議論這事 （著名外星人現身地點）
Alien unicorn. Last of its species.
其實他們還有最後一人
Griffin the Archanan.
阿查南星人，格裏芬
How's it going?
還好嗎？
Going? How's it going? That depends. For me, personally, things are good.
還好嗎？這個我說了不算，就我個人來講，還不錯
Unless we're in the future...
除非一會
...where the muscle boy argues with his girlfriend.
那肌肉男和他女友吵架
She storms off and bumps the guy with the stuffed mushrooms...
她氣沖沖離開，恰巧撞到了端蘑菇的人
...who dumps the tray on the sailors on leave.
托盤倒在水兵身上
A shoving match breaks out.
一番推搡後
They crash into the table. In which case, I gotta move my plate.
水兵撞到了桌子，若是這樣，我得拿走我的盤子
Or it's the future where the pastrami sandwich I'm eating...
過會我吃完這牛肉三明治
...causes me gastric distress.
會導致胃腸不適
Thankfully, your friend offers the antacids he carries...
還好你朋友把右口袋裏的胃藥給了我
...in his right pocket, so good. I'll be good.
然後我就好了，沒事了
Except in the future where I have to leave in two minutes...
除了一會我必須
...before he has a chance to offer me the antacids...
在他給我胃藥前離開
...so on the whole, I'd have to say not good. I am not good.
總的來說，我並不好
But that depends.
但不是我能決定的
K!
K！快來
How will we find this guy?
我們怎麼才能找到他？
What am l, a schmuck?
你以為我是什麼，蠢貨嗎？
He's here?
他在這？
"Here" is a relative term. He's a fifth dimensional being.
「在這」只是一個相對概念 他是五維空間的生物
They can live in and visualize an infinite set...
他可能在時空的任一點上
...of time-space probabilities simultaneously.
同時出現
Sounds like fun. Good work.
聽起來很厲害，做得好
Whoa, whoa, K, K, K.
等下，K，K，K
You gotta fake my death, okay?
你得假裝我死了，好嗎？
I can't listen to sitar music anymore.
我再也受不了這種臥底生活了
All right, I'll see what I can do. I'll talk to X.
好吧，我盡力，我會和X說的
K, I can't tell the women from the men.
K，我真的受夠了
May I see your watch?
幾點了？
Oh, it is 7:18.
現在是7:18
No, no, your other watch, the one your father gave you.
不，是另一隻懷表，你父親給你的
How do you know about my father's watch?
你怎麼知道我爸的懷表？
Oh, dear.
哎呀
This is the one where Roman is dead...
這就是羅曼
...and the gentleman at the bowling alley. So much death.
和保齡館的人被殺時在旁邊的表 充滿了死亡氣息
Such an infinitesimally small chance for success.
幾乎沒什麼勝算
K!
K快來！
Griffin, right?
格裏芬？
We're here--
我們在這…
Because of Boris.
因為鮑裏斯
We think he's coming--
我們認為他會…
To kill me. He'll be here in minutes...
來殺我，他幾分鐘就到
...unless we're in...
除非
...the future where he made the lights...
一路綠燈他能早到
...and is about...
他會
...to shoot from the door...
從大門進來
...in which case we're all dead.
不一會咱們就全掛了
Good, that was a close one.
那是比較靠譜的
K, I need a space gun.
K，我需要太空槍
The Boglodites...
伯格羅多星人
...consume any planet in their path.
走一路殺一路
Mine, Roman's, the Parlaxians'.
我的星球，羅曼的星球，帕萊先星球
I tried to stop them, but if we stop them here, if we deny them Earth...
我設法阻止他們，但如果我們可以在這阻止他 讓他們地球在地球全軍覆沒
...we can stop them. They'll starve before...
他們就完了
...they reach the next planet.
再也不會禍害其它星球了
How do we do that? Stop them?
我們怎麼做才能組織他們？
What?
什麼？
Sorry. I have something for you.
抱歉，我給你點東西
A gift. It can protect you.
一份禮物，可以保護你
I had to hide it from Boris, but if you find me again...
因為鮑裏斯要來了我得把它藏起來 如果你還能找到我
...I'll give it to you.
我會把它給你
Thank you. What a game! Amazing! It's a real miracle!
謝謝，多棒的球賽！難以置信！真是奇跡！
What do you mean? What miracle?
等下，你說什麼？什麼奇跡？
Thirty seconds. I have to go.
還有30秒，我得走了
No, we got you.
不，我們可以保護你
Negative possibilities are multiplying as we speak.
我們說話時死亡可能性就在增加
-Okay. -Twenty seconds.
還有20秒
All right.
好吧
We got it, relax.
我們應付，放鬆點
If your watch is broken and I have gastric--
如果你的表壞了，我有胃痛…
Fly! Find your place in the world!
飛啊！看看這個世界！
Oh, dear.
喔，哎呀
Boris is coming through that door...
鮑裏斯要從大門進來了
...in 12...
12秒
...11, 10--
11秒，10秒…
Wait!
等等！
Did you have chocolate milk?
你喝巧克力牛奶了？
Cindy.
辛迪
K!
K！
-Griffin! -Got him.
抓住格裏芬！
Damn it!
該死！
I'm good, I'm good.
我沒事，我沒事
What you got?
格裏芬呢？
Damn it! We had him!
該死！都抓住他了
Relax, Cochise. We'll find him.
放鬆，科奇斯，他跑不了
First of all, my name is J, okay?
首先，我叫J，明白嗎？
It's not "son," it's not "slick" and it damn sure ain't no "Cochise."
不是什麼孩子，滑頭 更不是什麼「酋長」 （亞利桑那州著名印第安酋長「科奇斯」）
I'm not gonna relax because we're running out of time...
我緊張以為咱們沒多少時間了
...and there's an invasion coming.
入侵就快開始了
You're not really recognizing my voicial intensity.
難道你真沒感覺到 我的聲音有多緊張嗎
But there was one guy who could help.
但有一個人可以幫我們
Hey, Griffin! Griffin! Where's Griffin?
格裏芬，格裏芬，他人呢？
Griffin. Where's Griffin at, K?
格裏芬，哪去了，K？
He's gone. If Boris gets to him before we do, that's no bueno.
他不見了，如果鮑裏斯在我們之前抓到他 可就沒什麼希望了
We need pie.
我們需要吃點派
-What? -My granddaddy always said:
- 什麼？ - 我爺爺一直說：
"lf you got a problem you can't solve...
如果有解決不了的問題
...it helps to get out of your head." Pie.
這時候吃點派會有幫助的
-Pie? -Yeah.
- 派？ - 是啊
Your granddaddy, heavyset man?
你爺爺體格很棒吧？
-A little bit. -Yeah, you know what?
- 還行 - 你知道嗎？
We've been doing smart stuff:
咱們一直做得不錯
We've been following clues, doing police work.
總是順著線索辦好案子
It might be time we do something stupid.
可能也有做錯事的時候
Something that ain't got nothing to do with nothing.
雖然一事無成，但我們盡力了
Now, I want some pie, K. I want some pie.
現在我也想吃派,K 太想吃派了
Let's go get dumb-ass pie.
咱倆去吃派吧
Sounds good.
好主意
Have any specials?
有特色菜嗎？
He'll have what he always has after he reads the menu for 10 minutes...
他總是盯著菜單10分鐘後才說出一句
...and asks about specials.
有特色菜嗎
A slice of apple pie with a nasty piece of cheddar.
最後還是要一份芝士蘋果派
I'll have the strawberry-rhubarb.
我要草莓派
It's my last meal, I'm gonna splurge.
這可是我最後一餐，浪費點無所謂
World-class serial killer out there and we're having pie.
世界頂尖殺人魔就在外面 咱倆還有心情在這吃派
What do you do in your spare time, stretch?
業餘時間你都做什麼？
See, I sense you're not embracing the concept here.
我看你沒明白我的意思
Pie don't work unless you let it.
放鬆的吃派更有利於工作
I'm gonna let it.
我正要嘗試一下
And you say we don't talk?
你說過咱倆不怎麼聊天？
You go ahead. Ask me any question. Anything you want.
來吧，問我任何你想知道的問題？
As long as it doesn't have to do with the case. Just let her rip.
只要和案子無關，什麼都行
What's up with you and O?
你和O咋回事？
Me and O?
我和O？
All right, all right.
好吧，好吧
All right, this is it.
是這麼回事
A while back, I was assigned to keep tabs on a musician.
前陣子上頭讓我調查一個音樂家
Mick Jagger?
米克·賈格？
He's in this British band, the Rolling Stones.
他是英國滾石樂隊成員
Rings a bell.
很耳熟
We believed he was on the planet to breed with Earth women.
我們認為他來地球就是為了 和地球女人繁殖後代
So I was in London and that's when I met O.
所以我就到了倫敦 也就在這時遇見了O
Just smart. Funny. A great smile.
她很聰明，有趣，笑容迷人
And we find ourselves in this pub, which is a bar, all right?
我們在酒吧碰見的
Warm beer and the worst food you ever ate.
啤酒是溫的而且食物非常難吃
We just played darts till the sun came up.
所以我們就一直玩飛鏢，直到天亮
Neither of us wanted to leave.
誰也不想離開
What the hell happened to you, man?
後來你怎麼變了？
I don't know. It hasn't happened yet.
不知道，那些事還沒發生呢
Come on, what about you, slick? In the future, you got yourself a girl?
你呢，滑頭？有女朋友嗎？
I got you.
有你就夠了
I cannot believe this, freaking New York Mets.
不敢相信，操蛋的大都會隊（紐約棒球隊）
Total losers!
簡直就是廢物
It's a rough time to be a Mets fan.
做為大都會的粉絲心裏可不好受
Tell me about it. Never gonna catch the Cubs.
可不是嗎 從來沒贏過小熊隊（芝加哥棒球隊）
That's funny. The Mets actually win it all this year.
有意思，其實大都會最後奪冠了
Oh, yeah.
是嗎
No, I'm serious.
不，我是說真的
I'm sure.
我知道
Look, three months from now, your buddies down there...
三個月後，那傢伙
...are gonna be calling them the Amazing Mets...
就得稱他們為不可思議的大都會
...and the Miracle Mets.
大都會是個奇跡
What?
怎麼？
What you got there, hoss?
你想到什麼了？
The Archanan said, "It's amazing! It's a miracle! I'll see you at the game."
那阿查南星人說過：「太神奇了 就是個奇跡，我看球賽時也看到你了」
I know where he is.
我知道他在哪
Told you to trust the pie.
都跟你說過了吃派絕對好使
If Griffin's here for a game, he's either too early or too late.
如果格裏芬來這看球賽 現在也不是時候啊
He's here. We just gotta find him before Boris does.
他在這，我們得在鮑裏斯之前找到他
It's time to give you your things back...
該把東西還給你了
...partner.
搭檔
You get some pie in you, you get all mushy.
吃完派你還有人情味兒了
I'm just tired of carrying your stuff.
只是槍太沉了而已
...Mets!
大都會！
Let's go, Mets! Let's go...
加油！大都會！加油！
-...Mets! Let's go, Met-- -Griffin?
- 大都會！加油! - 格裏芬？
You're just in time!
來得正好！
Unless this is the one where Robinson bad-hops it past third, it's almost over.
要不是羅賓遜的這幾次失誤，比賽就結束了
Are we missing something?
我們錯過什麼了嗎？
The game.
球賽
So this is how you see things? This is amazing.
你就是這麼看東西的？真神奇
It's a gigantic pain in the ass. But it has its moments.
這能力很討厭，但有時用下也不錯
This game doesn't happen till October.
這可是10月份的比賽
It's always October...
我能看到10月
...and November and March.
11月，3月的比賽
So many futures, and all real. Don't know which will coalesce.
當未來展現在你眼前，一切都那麼真實 你不會知道會發生什麼
Until then, they're all happening.
直到那時，發生轉折的一刻
Like this one, it's my favorite moment in human history.
就像這個，是我最難忘的時刻
All the things that had to converge for the Mets to win the World Series.
一切有利因素都在大都會這邊 讓他們贏得世界冠軍
They were in last place every single season until they won it all.
雖然每個賽季他們都是最後一名 但從現在開始就不一樣了
You said you had a gift.
你說有禮物要給我們
That baseball...
那個棒球
...thrown for the last out of game five, manufactured in '62 by Spalding...
就是第五場比賽最後投出去的 由麻省奇科皮的斯波爾丁製造的
...of Chicopee, Massachusetts, was aerodynamically flawed...
由於棒球皮革沒有
...due to the horsehide being improperly tanned...
正確晾曬導致存在力學缺陷
...because the tanner's wife left him...
因為制革工人的妻子讓他
...for a Puerto Rican golf pro--
為一個波多黎各職業高爾夫球選手服務
The gift?
禮物呢？
Oh, yes, of course. In the box.
當然，在盒子裏
It's the surprise. To protect the Earth.
這可是個驚喜，可以保衛地球
It's a shield.
這個是盾牌
Shield.
盾牌
Archanan. Arc Net. You put up the Arc Net.
阿查南星人，天穹網 你建造的天穹網
-How? -When that ball is pitched to...
- 怎麼用？ - 當球投給
...Davey Johnson...
戴維·約翰遜
...who became a player...
約翰遜之所以成為棒球手
...because his dad couldn't find a football to give him for his birthday...
因為他父親在他生日時沒弄到橄欖球給他
...it hits...
擊打時
...his bat two micrometers too high...
球棒偏高了2微米
...popping out to Cleon Jones...
球剛好被克里昂·瓊斯接住
... who would've been born Clara, a statistical...
克里昂本應該是克拉拉
... typist, if his parents didn't have an extra glass of wine that night...
一個從事打字員工作的女孩 如果他父母在造人當晚
...before going to bed.
沒喝那麼多酒的話
A miracle...
奇跡出現時
...is what seems impossible but happens anyway.
總是覺得不可思議，其實早已命中注定
I lost my planet.
我的星球已經被毀了
I don't want you to lose yours.
我不希望地球也遭受同樣厄運
It'll take a miracle, but if you pull this off...
它會帶來奇跡，如果你們成功了
...you'll be my new favorite moment...
這會是人類歷史上
...in human history.
最難忘的時刻
Oh, dear.
哎呀
I forgot to see this one coming.
我忘了還有這場好戲
Damn it!
該死！
Have these in the future?
未來有這玩意嘛？
No.
沒有
Get on.
騎上去
Keep gyro settings at zero gain.
保持回轉儀零增益
Balance pitch and yaw with bursts on the center stalk...
迅速扳動中央軸可以在 傾斜和偏航時保持平衡
...between 80 and 100 psi.
壓力介於80-100磅每平方英吋
I didn't understand...
根本沒聽懂
...any of that!
你說的這些！
-Gyro at zero gain. -lt is.
- 回轉儀設置到零增益 - 現在就是
Pitch and yaw with short bursts on the center stalk.
在傾斜和偏航時迅速扳動中央軸
I did!
我做了
Between 80 and 100 psi!
壓力介於80-100磅每平方英吋
Got it.
明白了
The Arc Net! Give it to me!
把天穹網給我！
This isn't the one where you get it!
你找不到的
-All right there, chief? -Hell, yeah.
- 感覺怎麼樣，頭兒？ - 還行
It'd be better with four wheels!
要是4個輪子就好了
Two is, like, my minimum.
至少也得兩個吧
What happens if Boris gets the Arc Net?
如果鮑裏斯拿到天穹網會怎樣？
Boglodite invasion, total destruction of Earth!
伯格羅多星人會大舉入侵，地球毀滅！
The box!
盒子！
Good boy.
好孩子
We gotta stop this guy!
咱們得阻止他！
I've been trying!
我一直在努力！
You haven't been trying?
你努力過？
Hey, slick.
滑頭
In the future, we ever do the Texas two-step?
在未來，還有人跳德州兩步舞嗎？
Yes, sir!
有，長官！
Did you get him?
抓到他了嗎？
Give me a sec.
給我點時間
Is he dead?
他死了？
Negative.
沒有
He got away.
他跑了
I got Griffin. Let's get out of here.
格裏芬沒事，咱們走吧
I feel younger already.
我已經有年輕的感覺了
You pathetic waste of Boglodite flesh.
你這個可憐的廢物
I'd kill you right now, if I didn't value my own life.
如果你跟我沒關係 我立刻就殺了你
-Who are you? -Look at you.
- 你是誰？ - 看看你自己
Every mistake I've ever made, just waiting to happen.
眼看我的過失即將發生
What happened to my arm?
我的胳膊怎麼了？
You lose it, shot off by a human.
被人類打斷了
No human could defeat me.
人類不可能擊敗我
You spend the next 40 years in prison, chained up like an animal.
接下來你在監獄呆了40年 像野獸一樣被鎖住
No prison can hold me!
沒有我逃不出的監獄！
They built one especially for us, on the moon.
這是他們特別為我們建造的，在月球上
No human has been to the moon...
人類還沒登月呢
...so they cannot have built it there already.
所以他們不能在那建監獄
Stop arguing! You can avoid all of that if you just listen to me!
別跟我爭！ 如果聽我的你就能避免這一切
You were defeated! You let it get shot off!
你輸了！是你讓我的胳膊被打斷的！
That wasn't me, that was you!
不是我，是你！
What's your plan?
你有什麼計劃？
Prevent the Arc Net from being deployed.
阻止建造天穹網
-Kill anyone who tries. -Good plan.
- 殺光想阻止我們的人 - 好主意
Didn't work.
沒我的幫忙
With my help...
你幹不成
...we'll get the Arc Net, kill Agent K...
弄到天穹網，殺了K探員
...the invasion will be successful...
我們就無可匹敵了！
...and we'll get to keep both...
咱們倆都能有兩隻胳膊……
...of our ar--! Stop...
啊！
...staring at it!
別盯著它看！
Listen.
聽著
-You all right? -Yeah. Thank you for saving my life.
- 你還好嗎？ - 謝謝你救了我
It's what we do.
應該做的
You still have the Arc Net?
天穹網還在你那嗎？
When you're being hunted by Boris the Animal...
情況越糟
...you get good at hiding things.
越能急中生智
This will save your world.
這可以拯救地球
Once it's outside the atmosphere, it gets...
一旦暴露在大氣層中
...a whole lot bigger.
會形成巨大的防護罩
All you have to do is deploy it.
你們得去部署它了
You mean in space? Well, how do you suppose we do that?
你是指在太空嗎？你想讓我們怎麼做？
It's just one small step.
這並不難
The moon launch.
月球火箭
Cape Canaveral.
卡納維拉爾角
July 16th, 1969.
1969年7月16日
We got six hours to get to Florida.
我們得用6小時內到達佛羅里達
Better get a move on, slick.
最好趕快出發，滑頭
Wait, hold up.
等等，聽我說
Not us. I'm gonna do this one alone.
不用兩個人一起 我自己去就行了
He has to be the--
他必須得…
Griffin.
格裏芬，噓
What do you mean, alone?
你什麼意思，自己？
I'm gonna go to Florida. You stay here.
我獨自去佛羅里達，你呆在這
I need you to trust me.
你得相信我
Trust you? I don't think so. Something you're not telling me, slick?
相信你？我可不這麼想 有什麼事瞞著我，滑頭？
You're not going to Florida.
你不能去佛羅里達
That ain't gonna happen, partner.
不可能，搭檔
Look, K...
瞧,K
...please, I will not allow you to go to Florida.
拜託，我不允許你佛羅里達
Stop me.
那就阻止我
You die there!
你在那死的！
Cape Canaveral. Apollo launch.
卡納維拉爾角，阿波羅火箭發射
Boris kills you there.
鮑裏斯在那殺了你
That's what I'm here for.
這就是我來這的原因
That's what I came back to stop.
我到這來就是為了阻止這一切
Oh, dear. We're in this one.
哎呀，一波未平一波又起
K...
K！
...I saw the file, I looked at the report.
我看過檔案和報告
I said I told you everything--
我說過告訴你的一切…
That's for lying to me.
這拳為了你對我說謊
Look, I'm sorry, man!
我道歉還不行嗎！
That's for telling me the truth!
這拳為了告訴我真相！
I'm trying to protect you...
我只想保護你
...man!
老兄！
The bitterest truth is better than the sweetest lies.
忠言逆耳利於行
He has to go to Cape Canaveral.
他必須得去卡納維拉爾角
He must deploy the Arc Net as he did before.
必須由他部署天穹網，這是他的命運
There's no other way.
沒別的辦法
K is the only hope in saving Earth.
拯救地球是他唯一的期望
Can I save him?
我能拯救他嗎？
Is there any future where I save his life?
有沒有哪個時間點我可以救他？
Yes.
有
But where there is death...
但在死亡之地
...there will always be death.
總會有死亡發生
According to you, I've done this before.
按你說的，我之前都做過了
So we know it's possible.
所以肯定能行
If you're half the agent you say you are...
如果真像你說的那樣
...you'll make sure I don't get killed doing it.
就想辦法別讓我被殺
So are we partners? You tell me.
我們不是搭檔嗎？你跟我說的
Let's go.
咱們出發
Agent K...
K探員
-...how are you? -I'm good.
- 你好嗎？ - 很好
Okay, group hug on the way to doing what we're doing.
等出發時再擁抱也不遲
This morning, man is about to launch himself on a trip to the moon...
今早宇航員將帶著人類的期盼
...with the expectation of landing there.
飛往月球並在那著陸
Look, I gotta ask you.
我得問問你
If we pull this off, fix things the way they were...
如果我們成功了，建造了天穹網
...O and l, are we...?
我和O，是不是…？
A wise man once told me...
有個聰明人曾經跟我說過
...don't ask questions you don't want to know the answer to.
不該知道的就別問
-I said that, didn't l? -Yes, sir.
- 我說的，是嗎？ - 是的，先生
Here they are.
在這
-What are they? -Jetpacks.
- 他們是什麼？ - 噴氣飛行器
Jetpacks?
噴氣飛行器？
No, no, no. We're not doing jetpacks.
不，我們不用噴氣飛行器
There's a reason we don't have these in the future.
未來也不會用
K, we gotta drive.
K，咱們開車過去吧
Can't drive to Florida from Manhattan in five hours, chief.
從佛羅里達到曼哈頓島 5小時可開不到，長官
Yeah, we can. The red button, standard issue in every MiB car.
可以的，按紅色按鈕 這是咱們專用車的標配
Press the red button, goes into hyperdrive.
按下它，就能以超光速行駛
No red buttons yet, slick.
別忘了紅色按鈕還沒發明呢，滑頭
Come on, man.
拜託，夥計
Do you know...
你知道
...how to work this thing?
這笨傢伙怎麼用嗎？
It's like with anything.
並不難
Just have to strap yourself in, hope for the best.
繫上安全帶，往好了想就行
Isn't that right, Miss O?
我說的對嗎，O小姐？
Unfortunately, it is.
很不幸，是的
You ready, slick?
準備好沒，滑頭？
Let's get it.
哦了
This is gonna be interesting!
這一定很有趣！
It's just minutes to the...
具有歷史意義的阿波羅11號
...historic launch of Apollo 11...
一切準備就緒
...with all going well.
即將發射
I'm so glad this isn't one of the times we explode.
咱們這次沒爆炸真好
One of the times?
這次？
Oh, we got company.
有麻煩了
The hell?
啥玩意？
Is that a battery belt?
還得用電池嗎？
All right, I got it.
好吧，我來
No, any reality that gets the shield deployed...
不，實際情況是你們得把部署天穹網
...is one where you tell the truth.
的真相告訴他們才行
The truth?
真相？
The truth is the only path.
只有告訴他們真相才是唯一出路
This is a restricted area!
這裏被封鎖了
Yes, sir, it is.
是啊，長官
Good day, gentlemen. Great day for America, isn't it?
今天是個好日子，先生們 美國歷史上偉大的一天，不是嗎？
My name is Agent J. This is Agent K. That's Griff.
我是J探員，他是K探員，這是格裏芬
We're from a secret government organization...
我們隸屬政府秘密組織
...that polices and monitors alien activity on and off planet Earth.
負責監督治理外星人活動 避免給地球帶來困擾
Here's the thing.
這有個東西
We have this special little metal thingy...
是個很特別的金屬製品
...that Griff gave us that we have to get on top of that rocket...
格裏芬給我的，我們得把他放到火箭上
...to prevent an alien invasion.
這樣才可以阻止外星人入侵
That worked.
這就行了
-Like a charm. -Sir, Delta Gate. We have a problem.
- 效果立竿見影 - 長官，德拉門這邊有情況
Three trespassers. No lDs, but they've got weapons, sir.
3人擅自闖入，沒有身份證 但攜帶武器，長官
Some kind I've never seen before.
這東西從沒見過
What breed of fool do you have to be...
怎麼會有這麼蠢的人
...to penetrate my site on the day of the most massive feat...
在如此重要的日子
...attempted by mankind?
闖入我的地盤？
Watched by God, the population of the planet and my own...
在上帝，全體國民以及
-...firstborn! -Colonel?
- 我的兒子面前 - 上校
Colonel, they had these.
上校，這是他們帶的東西
They said they needed to put something on the rocket...
他們說得把什麼東西放在火箭上
...for an invasion.
來防止入侵
Thanks.
謝謝
I got 10 minutes to launch.
還有10分鐘火箭發射
If you pose a threat to that rocket, you tell me now and do not lie to me.
如果這對火箭構成威脅 現在就告訴我，別撒謊
I told the truth last time.
我說的都是事實
Sir, this man came here from...
長官，他為了救我
...the future to protect me...
從未來穿梭至今
...so I can attach a shield to the top of that rocket and save the world.
我可以在火箭頂端裝上盾牌來拯救地球
I need your help to do that.
這需要你的幫助
Take them to the brig.
把他帶到禁閉室
You're slipping, Griff.
真有你的，格裏芬
Sir, if I may.
長官，如果可以
Corporal.
下士
You men are no longer needed.
你們可以走了
I'll take the prisoners.
這些人交給我
-Sir, are you--? -Dismissed.
- 長官，你…？ - 退下
Follow me.
跟我來
You did the future thing. What did you show him?
你用超能力讓他看到什麼了？
Only what he needed to see.
只是他應該知道的事
I have to go now.
我得走了
What? No, no, no. Come on.
什麼？不，來吧
You don't need me anymore.
你不再需要我了
All right, Griff, don't start flipping on me.
好吧，格裏芬，別逗我了
When Boris' arm is taken, the past will be as it was. K will survive.
當鮑裏斯斷臂時 往事就已注定，K會沒事的
He will not know you were ever here.
他不會知道你曾經來過這
All right. Arm gone, got it. Like a reset?
斷臂，我知道，就像復位一樣？
When that happens, go home. Leave.
當這事發生時 回到你原來的地方，離開這
You coming?
你還來不來？
Yeah, all right!
來
Anything's possible.
一切皆有可能
I can never bear to watch this part.
真不忍心看到這一切
Armstrong and Aldrin are scheduled...
北美東部時間週一清晨
...to set foot on the moon...
阿姆斯特朗和奧爾德林
...on early Monday morning, Eastern Daylight Time.
將正式踏上月球之旅
Where's Griffin?
格裏芬呢？
Doing his own thing.
有事先走了
Gentlemen.
先生們
This elevator will take you to the top.
這電梯能把你們送到頂上
T o get the Arc Net outside the atmosphere...
你們可以把天穹網
...you need to strap it to the escape rocket above the capsule!
綁在太空艙上方的分離火箭上 來接觸大氣層
You do not want to be...
火箭發射時
...anywhere near this rocket when it takes off!
一定要離得遠遠的！
-Questions? -No. Thank you for this, colonel.
- 還有問題嗎？ - 沒了，謝謝你，上校
Some job you got there.
你們任務艱巨
Hey, thanks a lot, bro.
多謝，哥們
What did Griff show you back there?
格裏芬給你看什麼了？
How important you are.
你們有多重要
You and your partner.
你和你搭檔
If everything goes right the way we hope it does...
如果一切順利
...I'm gonna end up getting out of here pretty quick...
我得盡快離開這回到未來
...so I'm not gonna have a chance to say a proper goodbye.
可能沒機會向你告別
If things go wrong, not gonna have a chance to, either.
如果事情不順利，我也沒機會跟你告別
So I guess win or lose, this is it.
能否成功就看咱們了
I see why I recruited you.
我知道我為什麼雇你了
You're a good man.
你是個好人
Good man.
好人
Man, what the hell happened to you?
夥計，你怎麼變這樣了？
I told you, it still hasn't happened yet.
我跟你說過 有些事還沒發生所以我也不清楚
I'll take this one!
我對付這個！
Naughty.
真不懂規矩
Get a pedicure if you get a second.
如果你輸了應該去修修腳
And liftoff.
去死吧
Just passed the two-minute mark...
開始進入最後倒計時兩分鐘
...in the countdown, and all is still go as we monitor our status board.
各項參數顯示正常
Astronauts report it feels good. Power transfer is complete.
宇航員狀況良好，動力分配已完成
Neil Armstrong just reported back it's been a smooth countdown.
尼爾·阿姆斯特朗報告倒計時一切正常
Hey!
嘿！
Boris, can you give me a hand?
鮑裏斯，幫個忙好嗎？
Hey.
嘿！啊！
Hey!
嘿！
You hear me calling you?
我喊你聽見沒？
Boris the Animal!
禽獸鮑裏斯！
Hey!
嘿！
It's just Boris!
是「鮑裏斯」！
You're gonna lose.
你輸定了
Let's agree to disagree.
咱們走著瞧
Hey!
嘿！
Boris the Animal!
禽獸鮑裏斯！
Right.
右
Left.
左
You're gonna lose.
你輸定了
Let's agree to disagree.
咱們走著瞧
Hey!
嘿！
Boris the Animal!
禽獸鮑裏斯！
Right.
右
Left. Left.
左，左
That's not possible.
這不可能
Let's agree to disagree.
咱們走著瞧
That's not possible!
這可不能！
K!
K！
I win! I'm better than me!
我贏了！比那老傢伙強！
That's my partner.
這才是我搭檔
That's my partner!
這才是我搭檔！
If we call this in...
如果把這個報上去
-...they'll scrub the launch. -I didn't see anything.
- 他們會取消發射 - 我什麼也沒看見
-Where's your partner? -He went home.
- 你搭檔呢？ - 他回去了
-How does that work? -You got me.
- 結果如何？ - 你懂的
Come on!
快走！
Get down!
跪下！
Bingo.
贏啦
Man, that is some next-level stuff.
夥計，那東西可真先進
You ever want to see more...
還想看這東西的話
...I know a top-secret organization that could use a man like you.
我知道一個絕密組織 正需要你這樣的人
I wish I could.
但願我可以
Thank you.
謝謝
I'll see you around, K.
後會有期，K
Look out!
當心！
Go ahead.
來啊
Arrest me.
逮捕我吧
Not this time.
這次不同
"Where there's death, there will always be death."
在死亡之地，總會有死亡發生
Daddy! Daddy!
爸爸！爸爸！
Hey.
嘿
Hey, my name's K. What's your name?
我是K，你叫什麼？
James.
詹姆斯
James? That's a nice name.
詹姆斯？這名字不錯
Where's my dad?
我爸爸呢？
What have you got there? What is that?
你手裏拿的什麼？
My dad gave it to me.
我爸爸給我的
We timed the launch.
可以看火箭發射時間
Where is my daddy?
我爸爸哪去了？
He....
他…
He went to go do something very special.
他有一些特別的事情要做
And he wanted me...
他讓我留下來
...to stay here and take care of his best pal.
照顧你這個小朋友
When is he gonna be back?
那他什麼時候回來？
He....
他…
James...
詹姆斯…
...if you look right here...
看這裏
...I will tell you the only thing you ever need to know.
我會告訴你想知道的唯一事情
Your daddy is a hero.
你老爸是個英雄
My daddy is a hero?
我爸爸是英雄？
-Want to take a walk with me? -Yes.
- 想和我去走走嗎？ - 好啊
James?
詹姆斯
You're late.
你來晚了
Sorry. Lost track of time.
抱歉，忘看表了
How do you know that song?
你怎麼知道那歌？
Drink your coffee. We got work to do.
喝你的咖啡吧，還有活幹呢
What do you know and what do you don't?
你知道你不知道的那些事嗎？
How do I know what I don't know?
我不知道怎麼可能知道？
That's a really good question. Did we go to Wu's last night?
這問題是挺有意思 昨晚咱倆去吳的餐廳沒？
Yeah.
去了
Boglodites?
伯格羅多星人？
Extinct for 40 years.
40年前就滅絕了
Perfect. Did we talk on the phone last night?
太好了，昨晚咱倆通電話沒？
You hung up on me.
你把我電話掛了
Yeah, I did.
是啊
But that was because of all those secrets...
因為這些秘密
...the universe doesn't know about.
宇宙都不知道
But...
可是…
...I've realized that...
我發現
...Iast night was a long...
昨晚的事已經過了
...Iong time ago.
好久好久
And, really, I just want to say thank you.
實際上只是想說句謝謝你
It's been my privilege.
那我太榮幸了
You know, there's a really high possibility now...
你知道嗎，現在來說很可能
...that I might know some things you don't know.
我知道的一些事你不知道
I doubt it.
我才不信
I bet I know what went down with you and O.
我打賭我知道你和O為什麼會這樣
She's a fine lady, but you know the rules.
他是個好女人，但你知道規矩
There's no fraternizing amongst agents.
探員之間不許過分親密
I think y'all might have fraternized a time or two.
我想你們倆在酒吧那晚也算挺親密吧
This is my new favorite moment in human history.
這才是真正最令我難忘的時刻
Unless this is the one where K forgot to leave a tip.
除非K忘了付小費
Almost forgot.
差點忘了
That was a close one.
千鈞一髮